# Oleksandr PIKUZA

### PERSONAL DATA

ORIGIN: Chernihiv, Ukraine

DATE OF BIRTH: July 14, 1988

PHONE: +380 63 1582832

SKYPE: alexandro.cn.ua

EMAIL: oleksandr.pikuza@gmail.com

# JOB OBJECTIVE

Looking for Python developer position. Prefer remote job opportunities

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with extensive experience of Python.

Python developer with 5 years of IT industry experience. Has an experience of leadership (6 Python developers team).

Has background in software engineering, web development. Responsible of system architecture and infrastructure design

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

MAY 2012 - PRESENT Python developer / Team Lead at JBS, Chernihiv

- System simmillar to CMS which is used for creating web portals and self-services in the field of telecommunication. Created products' structure consists of pages with number of a blocks with content. Pages and blocks are managed via administrative interface without any manipulation by the administrators. Interaction to obtain an information from a billing web services about displayed services/promotions and its order occurs through a SOAP protocol
- Online service for aggregation of restaurants, hotels, posters and billboards tagged by customer rating and feedbacks. Including search with complex conditions and social networks integration

OCT. 2010 - MAY 2012 Python developer / Team Lead at YuktiGroup, Chernihiv

- Daozon.ru B2b a trading platform where suppliers from China represent their goods for Russian business owners
- Sambuka.me Online service for ordering photo albums. Includes online editor for images/photos and API for offline integration with printing house, automation of ts processes such as printing, assembly and delivery of user albums

DEC. 2007 - Nov. 2008 Software Developer at Softline, Chernihiv

• Software developer for financial system (reports, forms, scripts) of Ministry of finance of Ukraine. Using Oracle Hyperion Planning

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAININGS**

2009 - 2010 Chernihiv State Technological University, Chernihiv

Specialization: Specialized computer systems (Specialist degree)

2005 - 2009 Chernihiv State Technological University, Chernihiv

Specialization: Specialized computer systems (BACHELOR'S DEGREE)

# PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS

Python / Django | The main language which I'm using in work process, above all in

web-development (with Django framework) but also in programming

watchdogs, scripts for deploying/updating servers.

JavaScript | Commonly used in work process. I understand what's going on, trying

to learn it in deep in my own time. I can maintain existing code and

make changes in it.

Ruby / RoR | Basic knowledge. But to learn it is interesting for me. Use mainly for

funny/pet projects.

Lisp | It's my goal #1 to learn it. Once I liked its ideology "Programmable

programming language". Every time I face it - like more and more.

# PLATFORMS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Linux / Unix | Extensive using of Linux both for personal and enterprise use

(distributions: RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu). Also MacOS X for personal use

at laptop

Libraries | FeinCMS, Jinja, Celery, South, Haystack

Databases | MySQL, PostrgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

Deployment | Vagrant, Puppet, Ansible, Fabric, Jenkins

Bug tracking | Jira, Basecamp, Redmine, Trello

Revision Control | Used CVS at University, SVN both at University and work, Git at work,

have been using Mercurial for the last 2 years whenever possible

## **CERTIFICATES**

Oct. 2012 - Dec. 2012 M101, MongoDB for Developers

Certificate

## LANGUAGES

Ukrainian mothertongue Russian mothertongue English proficient

#### INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES